<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fanged Games</title>
    <link>http://www.fangedgames.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fanged Games</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 14:09:57 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.fangedgames.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Turmoil: the Chosen</title>
      <link>http://www.fangedgames.com/post/turmoil-chosen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 14:09:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fangedgames.com/post/turmoil-chosen/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The chosen is someone with great powers and a duty to fight evil. Their moves are about doing what&amp;rsquo;s necessary and steel themselves against hardships. Their darkest self is about refusing help and carry the weight of their responsibility alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stats:eb106ce578625776e086307f4ada4a20&#34;&gt;Stats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add 1 to one of these:
Hot -1, Cold 1, Volatile 1, Dark -1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moves:eb106ce578625776e086307f4ada4a20&#34;&gt;Moves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mercy&lt;/strong&gt;: When you spare the life of someone you have a reason to kill, take a Cold string over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growing Pains&lt;/strong&gt;: When you fail to protect your friends, mark experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cold Blood&lt;/strong&gt;: When you gather your courage, you can roll+Cold. On a 10+ choose 3, On a 7-9 choose 1.
- You aren&amp;rsquo;t scared anymore
- You gain +1 to your next roll
- You gain a cold string on the scariest person present
- You can ask a question about the situation to the MC (MC must answer truthfully)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take the blow&lt;/strong&gt;: When you leap into the way and take the blow instead of someone else, roll +Volatile. On a success you are hurt and they&amp;rsquo;re not. On a 10+ you can choose to be Scared instead of Hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light the way&lt;/strong&gt;: Whenever your friends follow through on your commands or your lead, they can use the Cold Blood Move (even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have it)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To the books&lt;/strong&gt;: When you research a way to fight a threat, roll with the number of people assisting you. On a 10+, choose 2. On a 7-9, choose 1.
- Ask the MC a question (MC must answer truthfully)
- Gain a cold string on your enemy
- You aren&amp;rsquo;t uneasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-move:eb106ce578625776e086307f4ada4a20&#34;&gt;Special move&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone else attends to your injuries, they take a Hot string over you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;darkest-self:eb106ce578625776e086307f4ada4a20&#34;&gt;Darkest self&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you are in your darkest self, as long as you&amp;rsquo;re on your own, you can&amp;rsquo;t be scared or uneasy. You escape your darkest self when there&amp;rsquo;s no more danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;backstory:eb106ce578625776e086307f4ada4a20&#34;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to friends you can rely on for monster-slaying support. Name them and take a Cold string or a Hot string over them (your choice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone wants you dead. The MC gives them a name and two Cold string over you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turmoil: first draft</title>
      <link>http://www.fangedgames.com/post/turmoil-first-draft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 14:24:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fangedgames.com/post/turmoil-first-draft/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Turmoil is an unofficial fork of &lt;a href=&#34;http://buriedwithoutceremony.com/monsterhearts/&#34;&gt;Monsterhearts&lt;/a&gt;.  It keeps most of the interesting bits but it changes profoundly the way they behave. It takes inspiration from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.magpiegames.com/masks/&#34;&gt;Masks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.angelfire.com/indie/btw/games/rustbelt.html&#34;&gt;the Rustbelt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the core belief behind this rehaul is that players should never lose completely control over the game, even if their characters are helpless, but that control can be relinquished in some measure in order to make the game interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BE WARY: THIS IS NOT THE SECOND EDITION OF MONSTERHEARTS AND THIS CONTENT IS JUST FAN CONTENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conditions:698e58a815953b650f646ce2d71b8858&#34;&gt;Conditions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conditions are completely different from Monsterhearts. I liked the idea of conditions that weakened you such as in masks, but I wanted them more crippling. The characters don&amp;rsquo;t really know how to manage them, so they are big obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are easier way to get rid of them, mostly by giving control over your character to someone else, such as in the case of strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conditions aren&amp;rsquo;t solely triggered by moves, but by the fiction as well. It&amp;rsquo;s common to ask &amp;ldquo;wait, are you angry?&amp;rdquo; to make the player realize they should take the condition. The player is always the only one who can decide what conditions to take, but be honest with yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While you are turned on&lt;/strong&gt; you can&amp;rsquo;t spend strings. To remove it act on your impulses or give a hot string to someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While you are angry&lt;/strong&gt; you can&amp;rsquo;t flee or make a move on someone. To remove it hurt someone or bottle it up. You can bottle it only 3 times. When you hurt someone you can start bottle it up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While you are hurt&lt;/strong&gt; you can&amp;rsquo;t make 10+ on moves. To remove it seek help and heal or become your darkest self. If you were to become hurt while you already are hurt you become broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While you are broken&lt;/strong&gt; you can&amp;rsquo;t make moves at all. To remove it seek help and heal or become your darkest self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While you are scared&lt;/strong&gt; you can&amp;rsquo;t gain new strings. To remove it flee or give a cold string to someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While you are uneasy&lt;/strong&gt; you can&amp;rsquo;t make a move on someone or shut someone down. To remove it flee or fling yourself into easy relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-moves:698e58a815953b650f646ce2d71b8858&#34;&gt;Basic moves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the basic moves are used to provoke the other character into feeling something, while other are used to change the fictional positioning of the character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you make a move on someone&lt;/strong&gt; roll+hot. On a success they choose if they are turned on or uneasy. On a 7-9 you are turned on or uneasy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you shut someone down&lt;/strong&gt; roll +cold. On a success they choose if they are hurt or angry. On a 10+ they lose whatever hot string they had on you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you lash out&lt;/strong&gt; roll+volatile. On a 10+ they choose two. On a 7-9 they choose one.
- they aren&amp;rsquo;t scared
- they aren&amp;rsquo;t hurt
- you are hurt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you flee&lt;/strong&gt; roll +volatile. On a 7-9 choose one. On a 10+ choose two.
- it&amp;rsquo;s not a big scene
- you don&amp;rsquo;t give a cold string to who you&amp;rsquo;re fleeing from&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you manipulate someone with a threat&lt;/strong&gt; roll+cold. On a 7-9 they must choose 1. On a 10+ they must choose 2
- they do what you want
- they are scared
- you have to make good on your threat&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;when you manipulate someone with a promise&lt;/strong&gt; roll +hot. On a 7-9 they must choose 1. On a 10+ they must choose 2.
- they do what you want
- they are uneasy
- you have to give something now&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When you gaze into the abyss&lt;/strong&gt; roll+dark. The abyss will always answer. On a 7-9 choose 2, on a 10+ choose three.
- It answers to what you asked
- It cures you from a condition
- It makes you happy
- you are not uneasy when it&amp;rsquo;s finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;strings:698e58a815953b650f646ce2d71b8858&#34;&gt;Strings&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two kind of strings, used to influence people in different ways. You can spend them as currency to make the actions against the people who gave you the string.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hot string&lt;/strong&gt;
- Make a move on someone without rolling as if you made 7-9
- Manipulate someone with a promise
- ask a question from this list
  - what do you like about me?
  - what&amp;rsquo;s stopping you from being with me?
  - what&amp;rsquo;s your greatest desire?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cold string&lt;/strong&gt;
- Shut someone down without rolling as if you made 7-9
- Manipulate someone with a threat
- ask a question from this list
  - what&amp;rsquo;s your greatest fear?
  - how can I force you to ____?
  - what do you really think of me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;darkest-self:698e58a815953b650f646ce2d71b8858&#34;&gt;Darkest self&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The darkest self is a Condition unique to a certain Skin, that changes the rules making it easier to behave in a certain manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vampire&lt;/strong&gt;. While you are your darkest self nobody can use a string against you, and you can use hot strings as cold strings and vice-versa. You exit your darkest self when someone more powerful than you puts you in your place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Werewolf&lt;/strong&gt;. While you are your darkest self you choose whether someone is hurt or afraid when you lash out. When you make a move on someone the option &amp;ldquo;uneasy&amp;rdquo; is replaced with &amp;ldquo;afraid&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-moves:698e58a815953b650f646ce2d71b8858&#34;&gt;Special moves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special moves describe the messy relationship a Skin has with others. It may involve sex or romance or whatever interpretation the player gives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vampire&lt;/strong&gt;: when you deflect or refuse to answer questions about yourself gain 1xp. When you open your hearth to someone lose every string you possess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Werewolf&lt;/strong&gt;: when you claim someone as your own, they can summon you at their side whenever they want, until you claim someone else.﻿&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The roleplaying gloves</title>
      <link>http://www.fangedgames.com/post/roleplaying-gloves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 08:14:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fangedgames.com/post/roleplaying-gloves/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Roleplaying can be dangerous. Ok, maybe not &amp;ldquo;Juggling venomous snakes blindfolded&amp;rdquo; dangerous, but still, you can encounter some pretty awful situations and you can hurt yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re playing a game and you encounter a situation that reminds you of your recent heartbreak, or a theme comes up that makes you slightly uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg&#34;&gt;X-Card&lt;/a&gt; is a good emergency button, but it&amp;rsquo;s a nuke. Sometimes you need softer options, for example if you DO want to tackle this theme or situation, but you want to have fun, instead of anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a collection of techniques that can help you tune the distance between you and the game, in order to find the spot that lets you feel more in control, more safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re like gloves, that allows you to touch itchy and stinging things without hurting yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;character-creation:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;Character creation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most games have a character creation phase, where you build the characters you will roleplay. When you act out a role your brain doesn&amp;rsquo;t know you are just playing, and it will respond to external stimuli in pretty much the same way. This means that you can easily feel the emotions of your character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting.&lt;/strong&gt;
If the time and place of the game is closer to your experience, the gloves are thinner, because your direct memories get involved. Robert Bohl, the author of &lt;a href=&#34;http://misspentyouth.robertbohl.com/&#34;&gt;Misspent Youth&lt;/a&gt; once said that the sci-fi setting in his game is like a pair of shoes you use to walk on nails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gender and sexuality.&lt;/strong&gt;
Playing someone with a gender identity or sexual orientation different from your own can make your gloves thicker. If you&amp;rsquo;re a man, consider playing a woman. If you&amp;rsquo;re genderfluid, consider playing someone with a fixed gender. If you&amp;rsquo;re gay, consider playing an asexual. If you&amp;rsquo;re heterosexual, consider playing a bisexual, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race and culture.&lt;/strong&gt;
Playing someone who grew up in a different culture or experienced different things because of their skin color can make your gloves thicker, as well as making you understand them a bit more. This also works with wealth. If you&amp;rsquo;re middle-class, consider playing a poor person. If you&amp;rsquo;re white, consider playing an hispanic. If you&amp;rsquo;re black, consider playing an asian, and so on.
Be respectful, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;during-play:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;During play&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the gloves can be tuned moment-to-moment. It takes a while to train yourself to change them but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;behaviour:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;Behaviour&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way you make your character act is a good way to tune the thickness of the gloves. If your character acts in a way similar to how you would in the same situation, the gloves thin themselves. Conversely, if they act in a different way, the gloves thicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: I&amp;rsquo;m a game master, I&amp;rsquo;m currently playing an npc who just saw a giant-ass crocodile roaming the sewers. I would personally be scared as shit, babbling and saying incoherent stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m having a lot of fun. I decide to make them do the exact same thing, because I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable with the thickness of the gloves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m a little tired and I will make a pause after this scene. I decide I&amp;rsquo;ll make the character faint. I never fainted, so the gloves thicken because my memories don&amp;rsquo;t engage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m at a convention and I&amp;rsquo;m anxious because of all the people. I decide I&amp;rsquo;ll make the character be scared and saying incoherent stuff. The gloves thin and I start feeling more anxious and panicky. (this actually happened once)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-and-third-person-speech:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;First and third person speech&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking in third person helps you thicken the gloves. Talking in first person thin them. It&amp;rsquo;s as simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: I&amp;rsquo;m playing Monsterhearts as a cute little werewolf who just killed a person in her darkest self. I&amp;rsquo;m about to say I&amp;rsquo;m sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty comfortable so I act out a sobby teenager. My act is so good I feel even a bit guilty during it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I had an incident and I still blame myself for it. I decide to thin the gloves by describing my character from the outside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I had an incident and I still blame myself for it. During the act I actually feel so bad it&amp;rsquo;s not fun anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;touch:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;Touch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Touching other players can thin the gloves for both you and them, so be careful. Some people don&amp;rsquo;t like to be touched, so maybe ask them beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: I&amp;rsquo;m playing a vampire game, and I&amp;rsquo;m about to feed on someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I say &amp;ldquo;Ok, may I grab your wrist?&amp;rdquo;. The other player nods and I grab it and say &amp;ldquo;I take your wrist and I kneel bringing it to the mouth, to feed on your veins&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I just say &amp;ldquo;I take your wrist and I kneel bringing it to the mouth, to feed on your veins&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I grab the wrist without asking permission, making the other player uncomfortable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By knowing and using these techniques you help making your game safer for you and the people you play with. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s enough to know that they exist, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t use them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who are you?</title>
      <link>http://www.fangedgames.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fangedgames.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fanged games is a one-person collective with the goal of creating raw games that bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A raw game&lt;/strong&gt; is a text document with the rules to play it, not a nice book with uplifting images. It&amp;rsquo;s not that nice books aren&amp;rsquo;t good, but better leave that job to someone with the correct skillset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A biting game&lt;/strong&gt; is a game that compels players to keep the fiction in mind when playing. Another way to say it has teeth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>