<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fanged Games - careful, they bite</title>
    <link>http://www.fangedgames.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fanged Games - careful, they bite</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 08:14:56 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.fangedgames.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The roleplaying gloves</title>
      <link>http://www.fangedgames.com/post/roleplaying-gloves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 08:14:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fangedgames.com/post/roleplaying-gloves/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Roleplaying can be dangerous. Ok, maybe not &amp;ldquo;Juggling venomous snakes blindfolded&amp;rdquo; dangerous, but still, you can encounter some pretty awful situations and you can hurt yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re playing a game and you encounter a situation that reminds you of your recent heartbreak, or a theme comes up that makes you slightly uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyurl.com/x-card-rpg&#34;&gt;X-Card&lt;/a&gt; is a good emergency button, but it&amp;rsquo;s a nuke. Sometimes you need softer options, for example if you DO want to tackle this theme or situation, but you want to have fun, instead of anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a collection of techniques that can help you tune the distance between you and the game, in order to find the spot that lets you feel more in control, more safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re like gloves, that allows you to touch itchy and stinging things without hurting yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;character-creation:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;Character creation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most games have a character creation phase, where you build the characters you will roleplay. When you act out a role your brain doesn&amp;rsquo;t know you are just playing, and it will respond to external stimuli in pretty much the same way. This means that you can easily feel the emotions of your character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting.&lt;/strong&gt;
If the time and place of the game is closer to your experience, the gloves are thinner, because your direct memories get involved. Robert Bohl, the author of &lt;a href=&#34;http://misspentyouth.robertbohl.com/&#34;&gt;Misspent Youth&lt;/a&gt; once said that the sci-fi setting in his game is like a pair of shoes you use to walk on nails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gender and sexuality.&lt;/strong&gt;
Playing someone with a gender identity or sexual orientation different from your own can make your gloves thicker. If you&amp;rsquo;re a man, consider playing a woman. If you&amp;rsquo;re genderfluid, consider playing someone with a fixed gender. If you&amp;rsquo;re gay, consider playing an asexual. If you&amp;rsquo;re heterosexual, consider playing a bisexual, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Race and culture.&lt;/strong&gt;
Playing someone who grew up in a different culture or experienced different things because of their skin color can make your gloves thicker, as well as making you understand them a bit more. This also works with wealth. If you&amp;rsquo;re middle-class, consider playing a poor person. If you&amp;rsquo;re white, consider playing an hispanic. If you&amp;rsquo;re black, consider playing an asian, and so on.
Be respectful, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;during-play:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;During play&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the gloves can be tuned moment-to-moment. It takes a while to train yourself to change them but it&amp;rsquo;s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;behaviour:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;Behaviour&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way you make your character act is a good way to tune the thickness of the gloves. If your character acts in a way similar to how you would in the same situation, the gloves thin themselves. Conversely, if they act in a different way, the gloves thicken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: I&amp;rsquo;m a game master, I&amp;rsquo;m currently playing an npc who just saw a giant-ass crocodile roaming the sewers. I would personally be scared as shit, babbling and saying incoherent stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m having a lot of fun. I decide to make them do the exact same thing, because I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable with the thickness of the gloves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m a little tired and I will make a pause after this scene. I decide I&amp;rsquo;ll make the character faint. I never fainted, so the gloves thicken because my memories don&amp;rsquo;t engage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m at a convention and I&amp;rsquo;m anxious because of all the people. I decide I&amp;rsquo;ll make the character be scared and saying incoherent stuff. The gloves thin and I start feeling more anxious and panicky. (this actually happened once)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-and-third-person-speech:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;First and third person speech&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Talking in third person helps you thicken the gloves. Talking in first person thin them. It&amp;rsquo;s as simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: I&amp;rsquo;m playing Monsterhearts as a cute little werewolf who just killed a person in her darkest self. I&amp;rsquo;m about to say I&amp;rsquo;m sorry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty comfortable so I act out a sobby teenager. My act is so good I feel even a bit guilty during it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I had an incident and I still blame myself for it. I decide to thin the gloves by describing my character from the outside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I had an incident and I still blame myself for it. During the act I actually feel so bad it&amp;rsquo;s not fun anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;touch:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;Touch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Touching other players can thin the gloves for both you and them, so be careful. Some people don&amp;rsquo;t like to be touched, so maybe ask them beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example: I&amp;rsquo;m playing a vampire game, and I&amp;rsquo;m about to feed on someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I say &amp;ldquo;Ok, may I grab your wrist?&amp;rdquo;. The other player nods and I grab it and say &amp;ldquo;I take your wrist and I kneel bringing it to the mouth, to feed on your veins&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I just say &amp;ldquo;I take your wrist and I kneel bringing it to the mouth, to feed on your veins&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad choice&lt;/strong&gt;. I grab the wrist without asking permission, making the other player uncomfortable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:4ac0809d47c4812a55ed4bc28804dd35&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By knowing and using these techniques you help making your game safer for you and the people you play with. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s enough to know that they exist, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t use them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>