<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Fanged Games</title>
    <link>http://www.fangedgames.com/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Fanged Games</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 18:30:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.fangedgames.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>turmoil skins</title>
      <link>http://www.fangedgames.com/page/turmoil-skins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 18:30:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fangedgames.com/page/turmoil-skins/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-chosen:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;The Chosen&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chosen is someone with great powers and a duty to fight evil. Their moves are about doing what&amp;rsquo;s necessary and steel themselves against hardships. Their darkest self is about refusing help and carry the weight of their responsibility alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stats:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Stats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add 1 to one of these:
Hot -1, Cold 1, Volatile 1, Dark -1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moves:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Moves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mercy&lt;/strong&gt;: When you spare the life of someone you have a reason to kill, take a Cold string over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growing Pains&lt;/strong&gt;: When you fail to protect your friends, mark experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cold Blood&lt;/strong&gt;: When you gather your courage, you can roll+Cold. On a 10+ choose 3, On a 7-9 choose 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You aren&amp;rsquo;t scared anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You gain +1 to your next roll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You gain a cold string on the scariest person present&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can ask a question about the situation to the MC (MC must answer truthfully)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take the blow&lt;/strong&gt;: When you leap into the way and take the blow instead of someone else, roll +Volatile. On a success you are hurt and they&amp;rsquo;re not. On a 10+ you can choose to be Scared instead of Hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light the way&lt;/strong&gt;: Whenever your friends follow through on your commands or your lead, they can use the Cold Blood Move (even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have it)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To the books&lt;/strong&gt;: When you research a way to fight a threat, roll with the number of people assisting you. On a 10+, choose 2. On a 7-9, choose 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask the MC a question (MC must answer truthfully)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain a cold string on your enemy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You aren&amp;rsquo;t uneasy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-move:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Special move&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone else attends to your injuries, they take a Hot string over you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;darkest-self:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Darkest self&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you are in your darkest self, as long as you&amp;rsquo;re on your own, you can&amp;rsquo;t be scared or uneasy. You escape your darkest self when there&amp;rsquo;s no more danger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;backstory:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have to friends you can rely on for monster-slaying support. Name them and take a Cold string or a Hot string over them (your choice)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone wants you dead. The MC gives them a name and two Cold string over you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;ghost:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ghost is lonely and spooky. Their moves are about alienating others. Their darkest self is about craving and obtaining attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stats-1:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Stats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add 1 to one of these:
Hot -1, Cold 1, Volatile -1, Dark 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moves-1:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Moves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wallflower&lt;/strong&gt;: When someone don&amp;rsquo;t notice you, or ignores you, roll +dark. On a success gain a Cold String on them. On a 7-9 choose if you are Hurt or Angry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then choose 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vengeful&lt;/strong&gt;: When you lash out to get revenge, you can spend a Cold String to make a 10+ without rolling the dice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hungry ghost&lt;/strong&gt;: When someone dump their emotional problems on you, roll +dark. On a 10+ choose 2. On a 7-9 choose 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mark experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain a cold string on them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are no longer uneasy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are no longer hurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dissipate&lt;/strong&gt;: When you successfully flee by going through walls, gain a Cold String over whom you were running from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dead people can&amp;rsquo;t keep secrets&lt;/strong&gt;: You can spend a Cold string on someone to ask them to reveal a secret of them. If you use that secret to Shut them Down, you add+1 to your roll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-move-1:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Special move&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you secretly witness someone in their most intimate moments, perhaps showering or sleeping, gain a Hot String on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;darkest-self-1:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Darkest self&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you are in your darkest self, no one can see you, feel you, or hear you. You can still move small inanimate objects. When someone acknowledge your presence, they choose if they are Uneasy or Afraid. You escape your darkest self when someone gives you the attention you deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;backstory-1:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone knows you&amp;rsquo;re dead. They gain a cold string over you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You witnessed someone&amp;rsquo;s while they were sleeping. They gain a hot string over you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-ghoul:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;The Ghoul&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ghoul is a monster that feels the urge to feed constantly of flesh, sex, pain, fear. Their moves are about morbidity and death. Their darkest self is about fighting the temptations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stats-2:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Stats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add 1 to one of these:
Hot -1, Cold 1, Volatile 1, Dark -1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moves-2:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Moves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The hunger&lt;/strong&gt;: You have an hunger for (choose 1): flesh, sex, pain, fear. When you feed successfully you can remove a condition. When you ignore a feeding opportunity roll +Cold. On a success, you are uneasy. On a 10+ no one notices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disaffected&lt;/strong&gt;: When someone gives you a hot string, you can convert it into a cold string. You can&amp;rsquo;t do it later, you have to choose in that moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short Rest for the Wicked&lt;/strong&gt;: When you die, wait it out. Some hours later, you wake up fully healed, in your darkest self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Morbid&lt;/strong&gt;: You can spend a Cold string to ask someone one of these questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do you deserve to die?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was your lowest moment?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What makes you cry?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ending&lt;/strong&gt;: When someone listen when you talk about your death, roll +Cold. On a success they choose if they are Scared or Turned on. On a 10+ you gain a Cold string over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-move-2:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Special move&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone lashes out at you, you can decide to be Turned On instead of Scared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;darkest-self-2:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Darkest self&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you are in your darkest self, whenever you ignore a feeding opportunity, you gain the condition Hurt instead of Uneasy. You escape your darkest self when you feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;backstory-2:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone smells like love. Give them 2 hot strings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone knows about your hunger. You gain a cold string over them. They gain a cold string over you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-queen:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;The Queen&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The queen is the leader of a clique of other youngsters. Their moves are about control and popularity. Their darkest self is about abusing power and trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stats-3:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Stats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add 1 to one of these:
Hot 1, Cold 1, Volatile -1, Dark -1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moves-3:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Moves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get a Clique. It&amp;rsquo;s usually half a dozen close friends who look up at you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose 2 perks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are a lot (like a dozen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can defend themselves (they&amp;rsquo;re armed or trained)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They know people (who can sell them the cool drugs, or get them into the hot clubs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They share something (they are part of the same team or band)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are as family (they are ready to fight for each other)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose 2 downsides:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are few (like 2 or 3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are dangerous (they have no problem with violence and crime)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are scorned (by other popular groups)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are different from you (in a significant way)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They need something (from you, specifically)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose 2 moves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The shield&lt;/strong&gt;: When you shield yourself with someone from your clique, roll +Cold. On a 7-9, choose 1. On a 10+, choose 2.
- You aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid
- They aren&amp;rsquo;t afraid
- They aren&amp;rsquo;t hurt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many bodies&lt;/strong&gt;: When you make a move on someone and roll a 7-9, you can choose that someone else from your clique, who is present, is turned on instead of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And your enemies closer&lt;/strong&gt;: When someone betrays you, you gain a cold string over them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Puppeteer&lt;/strong&gt;: When you ask someone in your clique to do something for you, roll +Hot. On a 7-9, they choose whether to do it or be Uneasy. On a 10+ they choose whether to do it or be Hurt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Streaming&lt;/strong&gt;: When you probe the mind of someone in your clique, roll +Dark. On a 7-9, ask 1. On a 10+, ask 3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you think about ____?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your greatest fear?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your greatest dream?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your beef against ____?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s your stake in ____?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a miss, they can ask you 3 questions. You must answer truthfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-move-3:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Special move&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you introduce someone to the clique, they become part of the clique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;darkest-self-3:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Darkest self&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you are in your darkest self, you can use Puppeteer without rolling dice, as if you made a 10+. You escape your darkest self when someone in your clique stands up against you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;backstory-3:3f3d94671251276eef6e1e1ec7926eda&#34;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You really want someone to be part of your clique: Give them a hot string&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You feel like someone is a threat to your status. Gain a cold string over them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who are you?</title>
      <link>http://www.fangedgames.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.fangedgames.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fanged games is a one-person collective with the goal of creating raw games that bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A raw game&lt;/strong&gt; is a text document with the rules to play it, not a nice book with uplifting images. It&amp;rsquo;s not that nice books aren&amp;rsquo;t good, but better leave that job to someone with the correct skillset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A biting game&lt;/strong&gt; is a game that compels players to keep the fiction in mind when playing. Another way to say it has teeth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>